Jessica Parks

Data Scientist

Data Scientist with experience in genomics, data management, ETL, and data visualization. I've been developing in the AWS cloud ecosystem for 2 years and programming in Python for over 5 years. I use this expertise to engineer data platforms and provide reproducible insights from complex data.

Experience



DATA SCIENTIST

2015-present

AgBiome

- I led several development cycles to modernize our pesticidal protein discovery platform, and provide data and guidance for prioritization of the resulting proteins in lab assays.
- I am leading the effort to collect all lab assay data in our AWS platform, ensuring data robustness and enabling analyses.
- I engineer multiple aspects of our AWS data platform, using CloudFormation, ECR, S3, Batch, Glue, Lambda, Athena, Step Functions, etc.
- I develop dashboards using both Plotly Dash and AWS Quicksight to provide data and analyses to scientific and IP teams. I have delivered multiple products that enable data discovery and on-demand analysis.

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2020

North Carolina State University

 I compiled a data set from 20+ Ribo-seq projects and built a pipeline to process this sequencing data on a Slurm HPC cluster using Singularity containers and Snakemake.
 This allows the group to perform analyses across their Ribo-seq data and the data generated from other labs.

STUDENT CONSULTANT

2020

North Carolina State University

 I used Conda, Python, and R to co-create a workflow for a client to process DNA metabarcoding data on a LSF HPC cluster, replacing their previous time-intensive manual workflow.

RESEARCH ASSOCIATE

2013-2015

AgBiome

- I performed microbial isolation, stocking, and growth for pest assays; I led an experiment that resulted in the addition of a selective isolation strategy that has been used for about half of AgBiome's 80,000+ microbe collection.
- I identified candidate pesticidal proteins from microbial genomes using CLC Genomics Workbench, and developed a Python workflow to prepare the resulting data for patent filing. This protein collection resulted in multiple research partnership deals with other biotech companies.
- I led the project planning, user testing, and coordination with a software partner for development of a Postgres database and Ruby-on-Rails application. This was a multi-year project with a budget ranging up to \$1M per year, and resulting in a product used across the company for over 7 years.

UNDERGRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

2011-2012

University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill

- Awarded UNC-HHMI Future Scientists and Clinicians Fellowship for two summers.
- I performed a forward genetic screen to isolate multiple chemically-induced mutations in C. elegans, and used SNP mapping and WGS to identify the mutants.

Education

MASTERS

BIOINFORMATICS

North Carolina State University 2019–2020

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

CHEMISTRY AND BIOLOGY University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill 2009–2013

Certifications

awsAWS Developer - Associate

aws AWS Cloud Practitioner

∞Coursera ML Specialization (in progress)

Technical Skills

AWS Bash Docker

Git/GitHub Julia

Jupyter Linux

Supy ter Linux

Plotly/Dash

Slack SQL Trello

Python

R

Links

G github.com/jessicaparks
in linkedin.com/in/jessicalparks

Contact

□ 704-813-7970

@ jessicaparks21@gmail.com

O Durham NC

updated on: Mon Jun 07 2021